var questions = [

  {
    question : "Who is the only actor to portray Jason Voorhees more than once?",
    choice1 : "Robert Englund",
    choice2 : "Kane Hodder",
    choice3 : "Gunnar Hansen",
    choice4 : "Jason Momoa",
    answer : "choice2",
    funFact : "In addition to his work as Jason in four <i>Ft13</i> movies, Kane also did stunts as Leatherface in <i>The Texas Chainsaw Massacre III</i>, and played Freddy Krueger's gloved hand at the end of <i>Jason Goes To Hell: The Final Friday</i>.",
    image : "jason",
  },

  {
    question : "What was the first horror film to be nominated for an Academy Award for Best picture?",
    choice1 : "Jaws",
    choice2 : "Psycho",
    choice3 : "The Omen",
    choice4 : "The Exorcist",
    answer : "choice4",
    funFact : "<i>The Exorcist</i> earned 10 Oscar nominations in 1975, including a Best Supporting Actress nod for 15-year-old Linda Blair.",
    image : "horrorAcademy",
  },

  {
    question : "What real-life murderer served as an inspiration to <i>The Texas Chainsaw Massacre</i>, <i>Silence of the Lambs</i>, and <i>Psycho</i>?",
    choice1 : "John Wayne Gacy",
    choice2 : "Jack the Ripper",
    choice3 : "Ed Gein",
    choice4 : "Son of Sam",
    answer : "choice3",
    funFact : "Although Ed Gein decorated his farmhouse in body parts, he only admitted to two murders, and a whole lot of graverobbing.",
    image : "killerInspiration",
  },

  {
    question : "Ray Harryhausen is legendary in the world of special effects for...",
    choice1 : "making Dustin Hoffman look 121 years old in <i>Little Big Man</i>",
    choice2 : "<i>The Howling</i>'s onscreen werewolf transformation",
    choice3 : "producing the first practical blood squib",
    choice4 : "pioneering stop-motion animation",
    answer : "choice4",
    funFact : "The 2001 animated film <i>Monsters, Inc.</i> pays tribute by including a sushi restaurant called Harryhausen's.",
    image : "harryhausen",
  },

  {
    question : "The literary character of Dracula is thought to have been inspired by what historical figure?",
    choice1 : "Grigori Rasputin",
    choice2 : "Elizabeth Bathory",
    choice3 : "Tomas de Torquemada",
    choice4 : "Vlad Tepes",
    answer : "choice4",
    funFact : "Vlad (the Impaler) Tepes was ruler of Wallachia after his father, and used brutal tactics in his struggle against the Ottoman Empire. After his father's induction into the Order of the Dragon, the family gained the honorary surname Dracul.",
    image : "draculaOrigin",
  },

  {
    question : "What movie adaptation does Stephen King feel best represents his written work?",
    choice1 : "<i>Stand By Me</i>",
    choice2 : "<i>The Shining</i>",
    choice3 : "<i>Carrie</i>",
    choice4 : "<i>Firestarter</i>",
    answer : "choice1",
    funFact : "To this day, Stephen King is quite vocal about his dislike for <i>The Shining</i>, which is commonly regarded as one of the greatest movies ever made.",
    image : "kingWork",
  },

  {
    question : "<i>Suspiria</i>, <i>The Bird with the Crystal Plumage</i>, and <i>Tenebrae</i>, all directed by Dario Argento, are considered part of this Italian genre of mystery/horror.",
    choice1 : "peplum",
    choice2 : "rosso",
    choice3 : "giallo",
    choice4 : "poliziotteschi",
    answer : "choice3",
    funFact : "The word <i>giallo</i> is Italian for 'yellow'. The term derives from a series of cheap paperback mystery novels with yellow covers that were popular in post-fascist Italy.",
    image : "italianGenre",
  },

  {
    question : "Actors Lance Henriksen and Bill Paxton both share the honor of...",
    choice1 : "receiving Oscar nominations for playing vampires",
    choice2 : "being killed on screen by a Predator, a Terminator, and an Alien",
    choice3 : "being related to each other as cousins",
    choice4 : "being passed up for the role of Freddy Krueger",
    answer : "choice2",
    funFact : "Bill Paxton was the sole actor with this distinction until the filming of <i>Alien vs. Predator</i> in 2004.",
    image : "lanceBill",
  }, 

  {
    question : "In the original 'Psycho', interior scenes of the Bates house were shot on the old stage of what other classic movie?",
    choice1 : "<i>Rear Window</i>",
    choice2 : "<i>The Phantom of the Opera</i>",
    choice3 : "<i>The Pit and the Pendulum</i>",
    choice4 : "<i>Frankenstein</i>",
    answer : "choice2",
    funFact : "The Bates house did not actually exist; only two sides of the exterior are visible in the movie, and they were false facades. Interiors were shot on Stage 28, originally built for <i>Phantom</i> (1925) and later used for <i>Dracula</i> (1931) and <i>The Fast and the Furious</i> (2001).",
    image : "batesHouse",
  },

  {
    question : "How long did director John Carpenter spend writing the original script for <i>Halloween</i>?",
    choice1 : "10 days",
    choice2 : "1 year",
    choice3 : "10 years",
    choice4 : "He didn't write it",
    answer : "choice1",
    funFact : "Carpenter named many of the film's characters after friends and influences, like Dr. Sam Loomis, whose namesake was a character in <i>Psycho</i>. (The latter Loomis's girlfriend Marion, famously killed in the shower, was played by the mother of Jamie Lee Curtis, the star of <i>Halloween</i>.) ",
    image : "halloweenScript",
  },

  {
    question : "In addition to directing, John Carpenter is known for contributing what else to many of his films?",
    choice1 : "Poster art",
    choice2 : "Members of his family as actors",
    choice3 : "Special effects",
    choice4 : "Music",
    answer : "choice4",
    funFact : "Carpenter completed the musical score for <i>Halloween</i> by himself in only three days.",
    image : "carpenterDirect",
  },

  {
    question : "Acclaimed director David Cronenberg and legendary writer Clive Barker have worked together on exactly one feature film. What was it?",
    choice1 : "<i>Hellraiser</i>",
    choice2 : "<i>Videodrome</i>",
    choice3 : "<i>eXistenZ</i>",
    choice4 : "<i>Nightbreed</i>",
    answer : "choice4",
    funFact : "Cronenberg's own film <i>Videodrome</i> is paid tribute to at the end of <i>Nightbreed</i>, when his character is revived by a hand thrust into his stomach.",
    image : "cliveDavid",
  },

  {
    question : "What material was used for <i>The Exorcist</i>'s possessed Regan's vomit?",
    choice1 : "melted mint ice cream",
    choice2 : "a mixture of water-based paint and gelatin",
    choice3 : "watered down Play-Doh",
    choice4 : "pea soup",
    answer : "choice4",
    funFact : "The pea soup was mixed with a little oatmeal. Apparently the crew preferred Andersen's brand, as Campbell's didn't work as well.",
    image : "vomit",
  }

  // {
  //   question : "",
  //   choice1 : "",
  //   choice2 : "",
  //   choice3 : "",
  //   choice4 : "",
  //   answer : "",
  //   funFact : "During production, the refrigerator containing the animal guts was left unplugged over the weekend, and the zombie cast was forced to act with (and simulate eating) rotting meat.",
  //   image : "",
  // },

  // {
  //   question : "",
  //   choice1 : "",
  //   choice2 : "",
  //   choice3 : "",
  //   choice4 : "",
  //   answer : "",
  //   funFact : "",
  //   image : "",
  // }
];


// var blankQuestion = [

//   {
//     question : "",
//     choice1 : "",
//     choice2 : "",
//     choice3 : "",
//     choice4 : "",
//     answer : "",
//     funFact : "",
//     image : "",
//   },
// ];